const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the following organisms is the vector for the dengue virus?","answers":[{"option":"Aedes mosquito","bool":true},{"option":"Culex mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Blackfly","bool":false},{"option":"Anopheles mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Tsetse fly","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the reason for relapsing fever in cases of malaria by Plasmodium vivax and Plasmodium ovale infection?","answers":[{"option":"Trophozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Schizonts","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Sigent-ring cells","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the first-line medication for the treatment of enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":true},{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Co-amoxiclav","bool":false},{"option":"Meropenem","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of action of fluoroquinolones?","answers":[{"option":"Disruption of folic acid metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting cell wall synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"DNA gyrase inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of protein synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivation of RNA polymerase enzyme","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Cheese-like discharge is a characteristic of which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":false},{"option":"HIV","bool":false},{"option":"Candida vaginitis","bool":true},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 4-year-old child is brought to the clinic with a complaint of diarrhea for the past 4 days. On examination, the child is irritable and has sunken eyes. What is the appropriate classification according to IMNCI protocol?","answers":[{"option":"Mild dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"No dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Severe dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Moderate dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Some dehydration","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the etiologic agent for enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Paratyphoid virus","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":true},{"option":"Giardia","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the incubation period of the causative agent of typhoid fever?","answers":[{"option":"10-14 days","bool":true},{"option":"14-21 days","bool":false},{"option":"2-4 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"20-40 days","bool":false},{"option":"24-48 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the below-enlisted opportunistic infections is typically seen in HIV infection with a CD4 count of fewer than 100 cells/mm3?","answers":[{"option":"Oropharyngeal candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral toxoplasmosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes zoster","bool":false},{"option":"Kaposi's sarcoma","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"HIV-infected patients with a CD4 count below 500 cells/mm3 are predisposed to which of the following opportunistic pathogens?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium avium complex (MAC)","bool":false},{"option":"Oral hairy leukoplakia","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral toxoplasmosis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 6-year-old child is brought by her mother with the complaint of severe agitation and disturbed sleep at night for the past week. On inquiry, the child admits she has severe perianal itching at night. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":true},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the screening test of choice for HIV in neonates?","answers":[{"option":"ELISA","bool":false},{"option":"HIV p24 antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"HIV PCR","bool":true},{"option":"Northern Blot","bool":false},{"option":"CD4 count","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the incubation period of Mycobacterium leprae?","answers":[{"option":"14-21 days","bool":false},{"option":"1-2 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"2-4 months","bool":false},{"option":"Several years","bool":true},{"option":"6-9 months","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 30-year-old man sustained a bat bite to his arm during a camping trip. He presents to a medical facility 12 hours later and is clinically asymptomatic. What postexposure prophylaxis should be given to this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Rabies toxoid only","bool":false},{"option":"No immunization required","bool":false},{"option":"Active and passive immunity both","bool":true},{"option":"Active immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Passive immunity","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the following drugs is given with beta-lactam antibiotics for synergistic effect?","answers":[{"option":"Cephalosporin","bool":false},{"option":"Macrolide","bool":false},{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Aminoglycoside","bool":true},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 10-year-old child is brought to the pediatric emergency room with severe watery diarrhea for the past 2 days. On inquiry, the mother exclaims her child has been passing large volumes of rice-water colored stools, 10-12 episodes per day. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute gastroenteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":false},{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Cholera","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the first-line drug for the treatment of mucocutaneous leishmaniasis?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium stibogluconate","bool":true},{"option":"Pentamidine","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Paramomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Amphotericin B","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Cerebral malaria is typically caused by which species of the protozoan?","answers":[{"option":"Vivax","bool":false},{"option":"Malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Falciparum","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"The causative agent for enteric fever may remain latent in which organ?","answers":[{"option":"Gall bladder","bool":true},{"option":"Peyer's patches","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Cecum","bool":false},{"option":"Small intestine","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the gold-standard investigation for typhoid?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow culture","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":true},{"option":"Splenic biopsy","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A young female is brought to the emergency room with severe abdominal pain, nausea, and vomiting for the past 2 hours. She had a meal consisting of rice and curry at a local restaurant 3 hours prior to the onset of her symptoms. What is the likely etiologic agent?","answers":[{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Bacillus cereus","bool":true},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the most common cause of diarrhea in children?","answers":[{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Reovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A severe outbreak of bloody diarrhea is seen in a psychiatric hospital within the past 1 week. What is the most common agent implicated in such cases?","answers":[{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Bacillus cereus","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella species","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which antiretroviral drug is associated with hematological abnormalities?","answers":[{"option":"Didanosine","bool":false},{"option":"Indinavir","bool":false},{"option":"Raltegravir","bool":false},{"option":"Efavirenz","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of action of the drug clofazimine?","answers":[{"option":"Folate synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"DNA damage","bool":true},{"option":"Cell wall synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Protein synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Cell membrane damage","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 34-year-old male, farmer by profession presents to the outpatient clinic with vague right-sided abdominal pain, nausea, and vomiting. Laboratory and radiological workups reveal hydatid cyst disease of the liver. This is his second recurrence in 2 years. What is the treatment for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oral albendazole for 30 days","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery","bool":false},{"option":"PAIR therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Percutaneous drainage","bool":false},{"option":"Watch and wait","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Relapses are associated with which species of Plasmodium?","answers":[{"option":"Malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Vivax and ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Vivax and malariae","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 25-year-old male presents to the clinic with complaints of a painless ulcer on the shaft of the penis. He has no symptoms otherwise. Clinical examination reveals rubbery enlargement of bilateral inguinal lymph nodes. What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes simplex type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true},{"option":"Human papillomavirus","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the below enlisted antiretroviral drugs is NOT a protease inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Cidofovir","bool":true},{"option":"Talepravir","bool":false},{"option":"Ritonavir","bool":false},{"option":"Lopinavir","bool":false},{"option":"Saquinavir","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the following organs is not affected in mumps?","answers":[{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Testis","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the following drugs is classified as a 'fluoroquinolone'?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":true},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfamethoxazole","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the diagnostic investigation of choice for hydatid cyst disease?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasonography","bool":false},{"option":"MRI scan","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"MRCP","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with a high-grade fever, irritability, and headache for the past 2 days. During inpatient evaluation, he develops a tonic-clonic fit that lasts for 1 minute. CSF examination reveals gram-negative diplococci with pleocytosis and high protein levels. What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Neisseria meningitides","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus agalactiae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A histopathologist is evaluating a specimen under a microscope and describes it as 'spiral-shaped, with no gram staining'. Which of the following is the most likely specimen?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium leprae","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio parahaemolyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 2-year-old baby is brought to the clinic with the complaint of loose stools for the past 2 days. On examination, the baby is vitally stable with no signs of dehydration. Which of the following treatment options will be offered to this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Zinc suspension 2.5 ml/kg for 10 days","bool":false},{"option":"ORS after every loose stool","bool":true},{"option":"Ringer's lactate 100ml/kg over 3 hours","bool":false},{"option":"Stop breastfeeding immediately","bool":false},{"option":"Give antibiotic for cholera","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 5-year-old female child is brought to the clinic with loose stools for the past 4 days. On examination, the child is irritable with skin pinch going back in 3 seconds. No other signs of dehydration are observed. What is the replacement fluid and dosage to be given as per the IMNCI protocol?","answers":[{"option":"100 ml/kg IV Ringer's lactate every 6 hours","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml/kg ORS over 3 hour period","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing frequency of breastfeeding with 100-200 ml ORS","bool":false},{"option":"75 ml/kg ORS over 4 hour period","bool":true},{"option":"100-200 ml ORS after every loose stool","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the following clinical features is typically the first sign of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Reflex spasms","bool":false},{"option":"Uncontrolled urination","bool":false},{"option":"Opisthotonus","bool":false},{"option":"Trismus","bool":true},{"option":"Risus sardonicus","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 5-year-old boy is brought to the emergency department with uncontrolled muscle spasms and lockjaw. A provisional diagnosis of tetanus is made and appropriate therapy is started. What is the antibiotic therapy for this infection?","answers":[{"option":"Metronidazole and penicillin both","bool":false},{"option":"Benzodiazepines","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Human tetanus immunoglobulin (HTIG)","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 30-year-old male consults his doctor with the complaint of watery diarrhea for the past 3 days. He has to leave for a business trip and has heard of 'adsorbents' that help reduce acute watery diarrhea. Which of the following is an example of this class of antidiarrheal drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Diphenoxylate","bool":false},{"option":"Milk of magnesia","bool":false},{"option":"Kaolin","bool":true},{"option":"Docusate","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestyramine","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of action of the antiprotozoal drug albendazole?","answers":[{"option":"Interfere with larval maturation","bool":false},{"option":"Increases gastric motility","bool":false},{"option":"Increases activity of cell membrane pumps","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits protozoal metabolic pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit glucose utilization","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the below-enlisted antibiotics inhibits protein synthesis via binding to the 50S subunit of bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":true},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with fever and pain in his right cheek for the past 1 week. On clinical examination, unilateral facial swelling is observed. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mumps","bool":true},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Sialolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 30-year-old male, farmer by profession is being operated on for an 8 x 10 cm cyst visualized on an ultrasound abdomen. The patient presented with vague upper right-sided abdominal pain for the past 6 months. Surgical removal of the cyst reveals multiple daughter cysts. What is the causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":true},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the most common type of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Neonatal","bool":false},{"option":"Localized","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalic","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbar","bool":false},{"option":"Generalized","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Which of the following organisms infect lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Wuchereria bancrofti","bool":true},{"option":"Trichinella spiralis","bool":false},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the treatment of choice for Entamoeba histolytica infection?","answers":[{"option":"Paramomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Nitazoxanide","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Tinidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"The lawyer of the defendant calls in a ballistic expert as part of the proceedings of a suspected homicide. Which of the following is not true regarding this type of witness?","answers":[{"option":"A doctor may be common or expert witness","bool":false},{"option":"Skilled in foreign law","bool":false},{"option":"Can volunteer a statement","bool":false},{"option":"Describes what he/she saw","bool":true},{"option":"Draws inference from observations","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"A 24-year-old male commits murder via strangulation of his brother for money. What type of Qatl is this according to the Pakistan Penal Code?","answers":[{"option":"Qatl Shibh-i-Amd","bool":false},{"option":"Qatl-i-Khata","bool":false},{"option":"Qatl-Bis-Sabab","bool":false},{"option":"Qatl-i-Amd","bool":true},{"option":"Qatl-i-Jabr","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the correct legal terminology for a verbal statement made by a dying individual in front of a doctor narrating the circumstances leading to his/her death?","answers":[{"option":"Compos mentis","bool":false},{"option":"Dying declaration","bool":true},{"option":"Oral evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Dying deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Documentary evidence","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Bansdola is an example of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Judicial hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Homicidal strangulation","bool":true},{"option":"Accidental strangulation","bool":false},{"option":"Lynching","bool":false},{"option":"Autoerotic hanging","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the time period of formation of scab in abrasion?","answers":[{"option":"1 day","bool":true},{"option":"7-10 days","bool":false},{"option":"2-3 days","bool":false},{"option":"1 week","bool":false},{"option":"3-5 days","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"What is the correct terminology for an injury involving the superficial layers of the skin?","answers":[{"option":"Graze","bool":false},{"option":"Laceration","bool":false},{"option":"Abrasion","bool":true},{"option":"Contusion","bool":false},{"option":"Incision","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/infectious/2018","question":"Why is a dying deposition considered better compared to a dying declaration?","answers":[{"option":"Less chance of fraud","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of witnesses","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of doctor","bool":false},{"option":"In written form","bool":false},{"option":"Recorded in presence of accused","bool":true}]}]
export default arr